A lot of the big track-fies will only move meaningful assets on-chain
if they can figure out who the qualified custodian is
and if they feel comfortable that the regulatory framework is clear enough
so that internally the person who's saying yes please move significant funds over on-chain
that they don't get into trouble. Clarity historically has been lacking
now with the Genius Act passing I think there is a lot of hope that that clarity is coming.
Do you think we need the market structure build to pass because that will truly
mark the moment where the track-fies have true clarity on how custody can work,
how they can implement their custody solutions, who can actually hold these assets on-chain,
can that entity also hold crypto and the like. So once that build passes I think you'll see
even more movement of track-fies on-chain but the writing right now is on the wall given the Genius
Act. So the appetite of track-fies to start moving balances on-chain and to prepare for that
moment I'd say is higher than anything I've ever seen and I've been working with track-fies since
2016 on the topic it's night and day difference.
All right here we are with Ian DeVote, Chief Strategy Officer at Ando Finance. Ian it's so
great to have you on the defined podcast welcome. Thanks so much for having me it's a pleasure to
be here. Yeah so Ando is one of the biggest RWA platforms third largest in assets with 1.3 billion
in tokens issued. RWA has been one of the biggest and fastest growing trends in crypto in the past
few months so very excited to chat just to get started for listeners who might not be totally
aware of Ando can you explain what you guys are about? Yeah happy to. So Ando Finance is a company
that puts traditional financial assets on crypto rails. We also develop the infrastructure and
services to give these assets utility on-chain and to make the process of moving these assets on-chain
and move track-fies on-chain a lot easier. We started doing that focusing on tokenized
treasuries but we will soon expand into stocks and ETFs. Ultimately what we're really trying to
achieve is putting these financial products on-chain to enable access to a global audience that
historically has struggled to get access to these financial products. In that sense it's quite similar
to what a stable coin is doing to the US dollar and making it readily available to a global audience
we're doing the same thing starting with US treasuries and very soon expanding to US stocks and ETFs.
Awesome okay so what problem from traditional finance are you solving with Ando and you know
what's what's so good about putting assets on-chain so you mentioned one aspect with
you know increasing accessibility what else? Yeah so access obviously is the number one
it's not to be underestimated like people in the US in particular forget how easy they have it how
you know many people in the US have a brokerage account that they can access these stocks
treasuries money market funds and the like having access to a bank account is very easy
you're not worried every single day that your bank is going to falter whereas people outside the US
in many jurisdictions actually have to worry about all these things if they can move their
assets their savings and investments on-chain that is a significantly better soundtrack for them.
In addition once you move these assets on-chain you will enable 24/7 mobility of the asset
and allow you to kind of use them in DeFi in different ways take the example of a brokerage account
even in the US your assets are kind of locked in that account you can't necessarily move them
from one to the other if your brokerage account doesn't offer 24/5 trading to look if your brokerage
account doesn't offer you margin or if you don't like the rate on your margin good luck you know
moving it around once you tokenize an asset it's very easy to move it around from wallet to wallet
or from platform to platform kind of what we're used to in a crypto setting or if you want to
send your ETH from a Coinbase wallet to a Kraken wallet or name your exchange is very easy to do so
that whole experience for US capital market products does not exist but once you tokenize them that
becomes possible okay so speaking of tokens i love to go into more specifics of the assets that
you have right now oh you you sorry oh usg and usdy can you go into how both of those work
yes happy to oh usg was the first asset that we launched back in 2023 it's a tokenized treasury
fund if you want to hold it you have to on board with us you have to put your wallet address on
an allowance and then you can hold that asset at the time back in 2023 this was pretty revolutionary
because for the first time a tokenized treasury fund could be sent from one wallet to the other
24/7 as long as you were on that allowance list you could also put a smart contract so for the very
first time people could use our assets in a DeFi a smart contract for its use as collateral which at
the time was the first of its kind obviously that asset does have limitations in the sense that you
have to on board with us in order to hold it it's not very composable so since then we've also launched
usdy that one is a little bit more flexible in terms of how it moves in the secondary market and can
be compared in that sense a lot more to a stablecoin both assets pay out other yield on a daily basis
they're fully backed with other treasuries and treasury funds so the main purpose of actually
holding these assets is if you have stablecoins on chain stablecoins are great products but they
don't actually pay out yield so if you want to earn yield treasury yield risk-free rate on your
holdings you on board with us and you hold these assets in your wallet so it's the main difference
between OUSG and USDY the fact that you have to go through KYC and on board with OUSG and not
with USDY yeah so for both assets if you want to mint and burn them from us you have to on board
with us OUSG is just a little different to the USDY because no matter even in the secondary
market you can only send it to allow listed wallets USDY is a little bit different in the
sense that it moves slightly more like a stablecoin so in secondary markets users can send it to
other users even if they are not onboarded with us you can also very easily use that asset in DFI
the broader DFI ecosystem relies on 10 different chains integrated into believe 100 different
DFI protocols which is a lot easier with an asset like USDY as it is than OUSG so you can
send it to other wallets but but can you buy it permissionlessly on on a DEX or no there are
people who have deployed DEX pools for liquidity of USDY so people can I believe go on to a DEX
to purchase this but you know the best way to think about this asset is kind of like you know
circle in USDC if you want to mint and burn USDC directly from circle you have to on board with
them but after that people could use it in the broader DFI ecosystem including setting up the
DEX pool the main difference with stablecoins then is that you have that additional treasury
yield that is correct and also the investor protections of that asset are slightly different
when you hold USDY you have what's called a security interest in the collateral
though what that means is when something were to ever happen to on the finance is the issuer
we have agreements with third parties that make sure that if you hold USDY you have a claim on
the underlying treasuries so that if anything ever happens to us a third party can actually
liquidate those treasuries into cash and repay all the token holders to make sure that they can
recoup their balance is that the same way oh yes yes so it's this design in the fully bankruptcy
remote way that level of protection you typically do not have when you hold a stable coin some stable
coins not all stablecoins are equal to be clear so some stable to have this but the largest ones
typically do not so what you have there is an unsecured claim against the issuer if something
where that happened to the stablecoin issuer you're not necessarily getting all of them interesting
and how can you get that yield as a holder USDY for example yeah so we on the back end collect
the yields that is being paid out you know buy these treasuries on a daily basis we then manage
the price of the assets we set that up on a daily basis and that is essentially how the yield gets
paid out so every single day you hold USDY you'll see the price go up slightly that it's equivalent
to the interest being paid out on a daily basis again this is kind of better than what exists in
tradfi often because their interest gets paid out on a monthly basis we pay it out on a daily basis
if if in that sense so it's it's convenient because you don't need to kind of block a token in in
order to get yield it it just like kind of increases in price but it's harder to use as an actual
stablecoin right because like prices fluctuating so it's it's meant to be more like a like a savings
instrument than an actual stablecoin yeah that's one way to look at it it's similar to a savings
instrument you just have to get used to the price not being one dollar per se right a lot of people
get a little bit confused when they see that because they think why is it stablecoin depigged
it's not it's just you know we pay out interest that way technically we also have a rebasing version
so you can hold a version of USDY it's called our USDY that one stays at a dollar and instead
of the price going up your balance goes up on a daily basis the problem with that asset is that
you can't really use it in dfi very easily dfi smart contracts their internal accounting doesn't
really work with rebasing assets that's why we as a standard asset have the value accumulating
version but technically if a user really really wants to have an asset that always stays at a
dollar they can hold rebasing USDY okay so you've been doing this for a long time and recently you've
seen a lot more competition from you know like the really big guys black rock Franklin Templeton
Apollo just like really big names now participating in RWAs black rock has its own US treasury token
with Biddle how do your products compete with theirs yeah i don't really think we compete really because
it's so early we're all just trying to build some of the foundational building blocks that make
tokenized treasuries more helpful assets i mean Biddle is a great example of that quite frankly
Biddle in terms of its product structure is more or less identical to ousg ousg was just a year
earlier we'd clearly black rock looked at ousg and its product structure and said that's pretty good
let's copy that but their innovation at the time when they launched was that they implemented or
circle implemented a facility that was pre-funded with usdc so that any Biddle holder could actually
transfer Biddle into that facility and instantly get usdc in return that was pretty meaningful because
all the sudden people could do 24/7 redemptions back into stablecoins we then put a lot of our
backing into the Biddle product to also have access to that facility and have since built
on that concept the aggregate liquidity across multiple tokenized treasuries and have started
offering that liquidity to other asset managers and even including the the frankrim templetons the
wellington management's et cetera of the world so i'm not sure i would describe it truly as competing
per se i think we're all just building on top of one another to build some foundational building blocks
to make tokenized treasuries more attractive as a category and i believe you've seen that in the
growth of that category because over the past two years i think it has gone from one billion to
seven billion dollars right yeah usdy is probably a little bit different in the way that it is
structured and the fact that it moves more like a stablecoin i think that is a pretty uniquely
differentiated product but even on ousg i'd say we collaborate with the track flies more than we
can beat this up yeah because you know even up at seven billion it's uh it's seen really
important growth but it's just like a drop in the water versus you know the much you know the
trillion dollar um you know u.s. treasury market so there's still lots of room for all of you guys
yeah um okay but speaking of growth so um yeah you've had really fast growth
you started the year out with about 500 million um in assets and now you're at 1.3 billion but
that's kind of stayed at relatively the same level since around june so what do you think
explains kind of the slower growth recently i do think it has to do with like the bull market heating
up maybe people are less interested in more passive instruments and want to you know speculate
a bit more or you know how are you seeing um kind of growth drivers for you yeah i think that
definitely i mean that's a factor to it right let people are when a bull market hits they're
gonna overall park slightly less money in tokenized treasuries overall but i'm not sure i'd describe
it truly as a slowdown in its current state a lot of these tokenized treasury particularly for ousg
and the light deals they are they can be pretty large and so some of the sales cycles quite frankly
just take time so the fact that over a period of two months there's not a tremendous amount of
growth in the category per se i wouldn't say is a signal just yet of the category slowing down
i think it's more just the nature of how some of the sales cycles works in addition i mean
we just have the stablecoin bill passed in in the u.s there's a lot of emphasis right now to make
tokenized treasury funds genius compliant investors are waiting for it to be genius compliant before
they put more money into it but there's a lot of conversations right now even with the stablecoins
themselves to move some of their backing right right now is off-chain into these on-chain treasury
vehicles so i actually expect the category to accelerate its growth to be honest not slow down
interesting so what's missing for these funds to be genius compliant there's certain components
and stipulations in terms of what the average duration can be of the treasury assets that you
hold that quite frankly is the main thing so you know some of these tokenized treasury funds have
to just change how exactly they allocate into treasury assets some of them have to change their
mix a little bit in types of assets that they also invest in but by and large these changes
are fairly straightforward to make related to your point that these deals have a longer life cycle
i was curious about like who the buyers of these tokens are like where does demand come from
yeah i say it's pretty diverse it's a lot of on-chain native capital that historically has held
a lot of its assets in stablecoins but now realize that you know why before go the yield if you can
just park them in these tokenized treasury assets so there's some hedge funds there's some VC funds
there's some crypto-native foundations that are parking their assets in these tokenized
treasuries more broadly and increasingly i would say you're starting to get some even
some tradify players they're starting to put some of their balance sheet in these tokenized
treasury vehicles they then appreciate the flexibility of again putting that into stablecoins but some
of the trad finds are actively looking at that and then increasingly some of the stablecoin issuers
are exploring putting their reserves into these tokenized treasury products and you know what's
the plan to further integrate with DeFi like how are you looking at these partnerships yeah so
it depends on the products you're looking at oh usg because of its permission nature is slightly
more challenging to integrating to DeFi and that requires typically bilateral agreements usdy
is significantly easier to integrate into DeFi protocols and that had over time we've just
added usdy to more and more DeFi protocols or DeFi protocols have added themselves given
the permissionless nature of it so right now i believe we're integrated into 100 different
DeFi protocols on can different chains people like the use of usdy as a form of
yield bearing collateral particularly in some of the perks markets margin protocols and we
accept that adoption to further continue um okay so you you said demand is coming from a kind of
on-chain treasuries foundations also heads ones and VCs but you're starting to see more kind of
traditional finance also become interested in in these assets going forward how do you see that
evolving like what what will drive more of traditional finance on to you know have have more of their
balance sheets in in yeah historically the big lacking factor was just regulatory clarity right
a lot of the big trackfies will only move meaningful assets on chain if they can figure out who the
qualified custodian is and if they feel comfortable that the regulatory framework is clear enough
so that internally the person who's saying yes please move significant funds over on chain that
they don't get into trouble clarity historically has been lacking now with the genius act passing
i think there is a lot of hope that that clarity is coming do you think we need the market structure
build to pass because that will truly mark the moment where the chatfies have true clarity on how
custody can work how they can implement their custody solutions who can actually hold these
assets on chain can that entity also hold crypto in the lake so once that bill passes i think you'll
see even more movement of trackfies on chain but the writing right now is on the wall given the
genius act so the appetite of trackfies to start moving balances on chain and to prepare for that
moment i'd say is higher than anything i've ever seen and i've been working with trackfies since
2016 on the topic it's night and day difference really how are you seeing that everyone wants
to get involved my friend everyone's worried now about you know missing the moment because
these days i think people understand what a stablecoin is increasingly not everyone's there
but the whole concept of moving assets on crypto rails and making it available to a global audience
that's kind of a very easy narrative to understand and once you understand that for a stablecoin
you can then very easily draw the parallel to broader us capital market products
so if you look at the growth of a stablecoin and even the growth of tokenized treasuries
to date it's quite easy to see how other asset classes can experience a similar hockey stick
that for trackfi is a move that they cannot miss and they've always been comfortable putting the
brakes on as long as they could be a fast follower but the moment to fast follow is now
so there's only so many also crypto native companies that these trackfies can work with
right a lot of them do not have the capabilities in the house to truly start moving on chain
there's not that many credible crypto native companies that can help them make that move
and so there is a little bit of i wouldn't call it partnership fomo going on
but these trackfies are smart enough to know that the time to move is now they cannot miss the move
and crypto native companies only have so much bandwidth to support them so if they want to
start making the move they need to act now and you're seeing that on kind of the issuer side and also
asset managers so like you know funds who want to issue their own funds on chain and offer that to
their clients but also just like asset managers who want to get like just better yield or more
flexibility on under tokens like are you seeing from both sides yeah i think right now there's
definitely a move among the asset managers asset managers were kind of the first ones to make
them move in the first place if you look at kind of what Franklin Templeton did wisdom tree black
rock they were first to start issuing these tokenized funds and there's many more large asset managers
that are now working on their tokenized funds to move it over we as a company will soon put you
know tokenized stocks in ETFs on chain it will be to non-US investors in the primary market but you
know a lot of the asset managers are aware of that and then want to work with a company like
ondo to make sure that their products in a traditional form can make it onto crypto rails and be distributed
to that global audience like the concept of crypto rails is a distribution channel a lot of these
asset managers believe about you know two years ago already figured that out what you're now really
seeing are the banks that are starting to catch on and the bigger call it capital markets institutions
like the exchanges and the CSDs and the like and thinking oh boy we need to start making our moves
as well because the asset managers have started moving now the banks and the other capital markets
institutions infrastructures need to start while it it'll be an interesting and next kind of few
months especially you know hopefully if we see kind of those regulation like regulatory milestones
with them with the market structure bill I'd love to talk more about your plans to tokenized
equity so we've definitely seen a lot of movement on this front this year with Robinhood announcing
their tokenized equities for the European market there's x stocks on Solana but Kraken and Bybit
are offering it was also tokenized like Galaxy's their tokenized equity via security ties so
lots of movement there what what are your plans and how does it differentiate from kind of all these
just emerging projects yeah it's very funny to us now I mean we love it that there's so
much emphasis on tokenized stocks we wrote our first blog post about tokenizing stocks last year
in February and at the time no one cared right people were still working on tokenizing real estate
and private credit and God knows what else but we've always thought that tokenizing public
equities is the logical next step because you want to make sure that these assets have very clear
demand globally on chain and pricing transparency and with US stocks and ETFs that's what you have
so we absolutely welcome you know Robinhood making their announcements on tokenizing equities in the
like bar model there's different models out there right some people tokenized stocks and when you
look at the fine prints they're not backed one for one so what you're really then buying is a
derivative product we don't really go for that model we believe it is much better to always back
something one for one and even on top of that have a collateral buffer so that a user can always rest
assured that the token they're holding is fully backed and then some so our assets are always one
for one backed in the way that we issue them with the other difficulty when you tokenize equities
is how do you make sure that the price of the asset on chain reflects the price of the asset
off chain and you can offer both assets with a similar level of liquidity when you've looked at
some of the other models that have been launched on chain the prices don't really stay stable they
depict quite often from the underlying in large part because these models rely on on chain inventory
and on chain liquidity often in decks pools that people can trade in and out of because that's not
an easy way to instantly get the asset from the issuer just in time at the same levels of liquidity
and depth of market that exists in traffic our model is very different in the sense that we have
found a way to more or less put these assets on chain just in time so that anyone who's looking
to purchase can go to you know our collection our ecosystem and acquire these assets at the same
prices and the same level of liquidity as is available on track five so when people buy you know these
ondo tokenized stocks and ETFs they can rest assured that the price they get is more is the same price
as they would be able to get in a brokerage account and that fundamentally is incredibly
important for the trusting the asset and making sure that what you buy gives you the right economic
exposure to the underlying asset at the right price the PR genius is a top crypto PR and growth
marketing agency helping brands globally with expert PR and strategic growth marketing they've
worked with 300 plus projects like movement labs and IO.net unlike traditional agencies they
charge only on performance their services include earned PR opportunities and marketing services to
help boost wallet holders and organic ex followers learn more at www.pr genius.com
In your model is the actual owner of the equity still ondo or is it the token holder does the token
holder holder have um have rights to the company like can it kind of participate in governance like
can it kind of redeem their their token for the actual stock eventually yes great question because
there's been a debate on that in which models kind of better so our tokens are issued as wrappers
meaning that what you hold on chain is the economic exposure to the underlying it is not the same as
holding the exact stock that model is very similar to a stablecoin right when you hold a stablecoin
you don't hold the same you know bank dollar as it is sitting in a bank account you essentially
have economic exposure to that dollar so you want to make sure that that stablecoin you hold
you always have an ability to redeem it for one dollar and similarly our tokens as you hold them
you have the ability to redeem them for the dollar value of the stock that it represents okay for the
dollar value but not for the actual stock no not for the underlying stock that model if you want to
have the actual underlying stock on chain that requires native issuance and so you have the likes
of a super state that is going after that as you previously mentioned the problem with that model
right now is that it requires the actual company that the stock represents to agree and issue the
stock on chain so certain crypto native companies have done that like galaxy and there's quite a few
more coming but yes not a scalable way to put broader us capital markets on chain i mean think
about the stablecoin and native issuance would have been the same as a bank agreeing to put their
native deposits on chain and then make it freely available to a global audience that clearly didn't
happen you had companies like tether and circle that agreed to put a dollar in a bank account
and have a token on chain that represented that backing and always make sure that you could transfer
it into the you know dollar value over the token our model is very similar in that it is much more
scalable it allows us to put the broader set of you know a thousand plus us equities and ETFs
on chain for a global audience but that requires the rapid format which is in and of itself no issue
whatsoever as long as what you hold is sufficiently backed has a collateral buffer and actually gives
you a security interest in the underlying which is what our model provides and that includes like
say if the company pays out dividends would that be included would that be reflected in the price
yes so when a company pays out dividends we automatically reinvest the underlying and the price of the
token on chain as a result will move up because it gives you more rights to more underlying stocks
that are backing it it's quite similar to what we previously discussed with USDY when treasury
assets pay out interest to us we invested into more treasuries so the price of the asset goes up
you always have economic exposure to the treasuries and the yield that it's pays similar for our token
i stocks and ETFs we will reinvest the dividends after withholding the appropriate withholding
taxes and as a result the token you hold is going to go up in value so you always have the
full economic exposure to the underlying so i see so this is when it is expected to go alive yes
you can expect more from us so in the next couple of weeks publicly we've stated by the end of the
summer which is coming up soon nice okay and and you said a hundred plus stocks will be available
that's right at launch we will have over a hundred stocks and ETFs available and we'll soon rapidly
expand that by the end of the year we end to be at a thousand or so and where will people be able
to trade them we will launch on main Ethereum for starters we will expand that to Solana and
the B&B chain pretty soon after that we are working with a lot of the centralized exchanges
as well that are interested in listing our assets so people with an exchange account can
we'll be able to buy it and you know as mentioned previously these assets are structured in the
secondary market as permissionless bear instruments so we expect people to use them in DeFi and find
out ways to have them interpreted into the DeFi ecosystem which may open up more access so i think
tokenized stocks kind of make sense in theory but we haven't really seen that market take off
very much like it it's been tried before i i agree like recently the big change has been more
regulatory clarity but you know like synthetics was probably the first one to try this i think like
back in 2019 it had like s apple or you know s whatever stock and that market was pretty small
then obviously there was a mirror in the tereco system and that got shut down for you know regulatory
reasons and then more recently the x stocks i don't know i think they've been off to a kind of a slow
start like i saw a report that said that the first like two months had like around 500 million
of and liquidity and that's like a day's worth of trading in Solana you know i think the total
tbl of these assets is even lower right yeah it's less than 50 million so i would agree that they
are off to a slow start i will think the critical thing to highlight though is that in all of the
models that have previously been tried they they either did not have the right legal structure
and backing right like when you were holding an asset that was issued on synthetics or the
mirror protocol it was just really synthetic exposure that was backed by nothing a lot of people
don't not feel comfortable with that and rightfully so recently with the other models at least in
some it is backed one for one but there the issue so far has been these prices do not stay pegged to
the underlying stock so you as an investor cannot really be confident that what you're buying truly
is the underlying price it's like buying a stable coin at you know 1.05 or 1.10 though one's going
to buy a stable coin if they can't risk to share it that a dollar is a dollar and they're not over
paying oh i think in part yes the adoption has been slow we would argue that that is because
none of the existing product structures truly has met the need for both the right legal structure
the right investor protections and the right liquidity and pricing model on chain they were
pretty confident in our model then it will be the first to achieve all of those things do you think
the demand comes from just like retail crypto holders who just you know maybe they're not us based
on they want exposure to us equities for example yes we believe the first cohort of users is going
to be the same people who have figured out that a stable coin is an easy way to get access to the
u.s dollar and some point will want to have access to us capital markets we also expect quite a few
crypto exchanges to start listing these stocks it's a lot easier for a crypto exchange to list
tokenized stocks than it is for them to listed via a normal clearing broker and have to work with
fiat rails and banking it's it's significantly easier if you can do all of that with tokenized stocks
do the settlement and stable coins you know it's in much easier integration for them so we do
expect quite a few crypto exchanges to list these tokenized stocks and for the demand as a result
to be that retail audience that now has access to us capital markets that they previously did not
but it's very possible just to caveat all that i guess a little bit when you look at stable
coins and tokenized treasuries like the adoption it happens it accelerates at a certain point but
it's still a slow process so if you were to ask me how big do i expect tokenized stocks to be
you know this year i don't think we'll be at the billions in tvl i think we'll be probably more
in the hundreds of millions next year we'll probably be in the billions and after that hopefully we
see accelerated growth but typically these things do take a little bit of time because there's just
a lot of user education that's required right people want to better understand how does this
work what am i actually holding it takes time to have DeFi integrations for these things to give
them utility and to really make the on-chain assets better than what exists in a normal brokerage
account that all just takes a little bit of time and with that increased utility will come better
adoption yeah that makes sense shifting gears a little bit and you announced back in i think
February the on-the-layer one just curious uh you know what what's the status of that like is it
being used and for what like what's what's happening there yeah um very much so so the on-the-chain
testnet went live earlier this year the production pilots are already in flight we had the first
transaction on that testnet was in a collaboration with JP Morgan we had a tokenized treasury settled
against cash that was available on JP Morgan to connect this platform it was kind of a first of
its kind with a bridge between private banking reels that operate 24/7 as well as a public blockchain
albeit in testnet but that was very helpful for us to just do an initial proof of concept with JP
Morgan and it it amplifies what ultimately the vision is for the on-o-chain say number one it is
the integrations into traffic that are needed in order to move towards 24/7 capital markets and in
parallel it's building out a DeFi ecosystem that can work with tokenized stocks and ETFs and really
put brokerage on-chain in the way that users are used to the current DeFi ecosystem is
very good very robust i'm a big user of DeFi myself but i don't think it's built to actually
support a thousand different stocks in the ETFs at scale 24/7 so we're gonna have to rethink how
certain DeFi protocols will work and that's the stuff that we're trying to incubate on the on-the-chain
so it's very actively being worked on more on that later in where to come so is it still in testnet
it is still in testnet okay and so right now the status is you are developing DeFi protocols on top
of this layer one testnet we are working with a lot of the trad finds to have the right hooks
into the trad find networks so that any transaction involving securities on-chain can also have the
right you know settlement leg and trad fi or the right transfer agent integrations into trad fi
so we're actively working on building those integrations with our trad fi partners as well
as developing a select DeFi ecosystem that is going to give utility to these tokenized stocks
any too can you can you give me an example of how you envision it like a use case that you see
working well in your layer one yeah so one of the key things that people expect to do with tokenized
stocks in ETFs really is margin right people want to be able to pledge their tokenized stock in ETFs
collateral and take out a loan against that whether they want to buy a house or do something else with
it tvd a lot of people also actually want to take bigger margin maybe even take leverage on
these assets in a normal brokerage environment you know you can hold a thousand different assets
your brokerage account will just tell you here's how much margin you have available here's the
rate you get ta-da in DeFi though doing something like that for a thousand different stocks and ETFs
and doing that at a cost of capital that is competitive with trad fi is very very challenging to do
most DeFi protocols are not built to support a thousand assets and if you want to have these
liquidity pools in DeFi for margin all pre-funded in USDC that is not paying out any yield to the
holder that's going to be very very costly so it's most likely going to be pretty expensive
and difficult to compete with trad fi rates if that is the DeFi model that you have to rely on
i think the way we're thinking about DeFi is going to be slightly different or augmented in the
sense that what it's really going to be about is ensuring that whatever user wants to do if that's
margin or something else they can really tap into the existing DeFi liquidity that exists on chain
but also the trad fi systems that have already built to facilitate some of these use cases
like margin the way margin works in trad fi is very established there's a bunch of people who are
willing to do you know this essentially prime brokerage the moving prime brokerage on chain
requires the right integrations into these trad fi venues making sure that they can operate 24/7
as needed because on chain DeFi obviously you're going to need 25 and once we have the right
integrations i think it's going to be possible to have the best of the on chain DeFi world but also
really have the trad fi rails and existing liquidity in trad fi be available for those DeFi use cases
interesting do you expect to compete with hyper liquid which does something similar with
perpetuals and offers this kind of you know margin it's a great question because people in crypto
right now love perch because it is a capital efficient way to get leverage on assets in trad fi people
have found different ways via prime brokerage you can get margin you can get leverage believe
up to 20x on stocks but in a very different way and so i think over time it's going to be very
interesting to see what actually provides the best type of exposure what provides you with the best
cost of capital to get leverage on some of these assets and that may very well end up being
perpetuals it may very well end up being similar to a prime brokerage model i don't know but i think
it's going to be very interesting to see how that plays out and how ultimately maybe all of these
rates start to diverge so that the rate available the cost of capital on chain is actually the same
cost of capital as in trad fi we're pretty far away from that quickly interesting okay so this
will be like an alternative way to get leverage on tokens alternative to perpetuals i mean that's
one way to describe it yes interesting when is there a timeline for mainnet when mainnet yeah
when mainnet right i'm quite hesitant to put a timeline on that because in some of these things
we requires the right trad fi integrations and as much as ondo can move very quickly some of our
trad fi partners cannot so i'm typically very hesitant to put a timeline on that but rest assured
it is being worked on very interesting okay well i can't wait to see more news on that front okay
now talking about real world assets more broadly so we've talked about money market funds equities
what are kind of the the next categories that you think make sense to come on to yeah i mean we're
very early innings of tokenization of equities right like fundamentally at ondo we believe that
tokenization makes sense to do two things number one is you want to enable access to a global
audience by putting the asset on crypto rills and number two is you want to enable these assets
as some form of collateral on chain and collateral on chain can be used for a live variety of purposes
you can use it for margin you can use it for staking you could use it for a live variety of ways but
those are the big two reasons why you would put an asset on chain in the first place when you look
at both of those having the right pricing transparency is actually very important for both people are
not going to buy an asset that they have difficulty understanding what the value of that thing is
and if the value of the thing is not entirely clear no serious d5 protocol is going to allow
you to use it as actual collateral or the haircut they would put on that is so absurdly high that
it limits the use of it quite significantly as a result you end up with assets traditional
financial assets that have a lot of liquidity in traditional markets and as a result very good
price discovery that ends up being you know obviously cash the dollars a dollar hence stable
coins took off tokenized treasuries hence tokenized treasuries were the next iteration of that equities
stocks ETFs very liquid traditional markets and then there's probably a few more like commodities
right some of the fixed income products maybe but you know there's still a lot of talk about
tokenizing real estate from private credit broader private assets i think there you start to run
into difficulty on how much are these things actually worth and how do you create price
transparency and price discovery in these assets so anything that's liquid in traditional markets
that has a lot of price discovery we believe that that makes sense to move on chain anything else i
think will be slower in adoption and tbd and whether interesting okay so do you do you think
that eventually all assets will come on chain or or do you think that like what would you just said
i mean we're talking about like in a really long timeline you know decades um yeah really long
timeline there are ways to solve the price discovery issue even for liquid assets as technology
evolves right there are ways to almost instantly price real estate for example as long as you have
the right information at your fingertips so over time will most assets move on chain probably yes
because the infrastructure is just significantly better than what exists right now but the sequencing
of the assets i think you'll have obviously stable coins treasuries and then you know public
equities kind of these in the leg which is where we have focused before the other assets move over
i will say though the the market size of those liquid assets is big enough to i think testify
everyone's demand for quite some time if you look at the total market size of um you know publicly
listed securities globally you're at 130 140 trillion though i do think um that that's enough
to tackle first or most yeah and and that's a good segue i wanted to ask you how big to do the
envision the rwa market will be next five years right now it's at 26 billion yeah i think you know
i do expect to see pretty exponential growth in rwa's overall particularly as the track flies
and trackline infrastructure moves on chain that is starting to happen it's not 100 there
like the big difficulty when you tokenize an rwa is how do you take the liquidity that
exists in off-chain venues and easily put that over to an on-chain venue so that you don't have to
duplicate that liquidity because that's very costly you also want to make sure that these
stratified systems can operate 24/7 because on-chain operates 24/7 if they don't both operate 24/7
you have some sort of liquidity mismatch as an issuer that's the thing that keeps us up at night
um so we're almost there i think we're starting to definitely build the systems and bridge that
liquidity mismatch that probably gets solved in the next two years once that's truly solved
i think gold bets are off and you're going to see things move on chain in the tunes of hundreds of
billions if not a trillion dollars so you know where is it going to be in five years any prediction
i make is inherently going to be wrong but i think it may actually surprise a lot of people on the
upside interesting okay now to wrap up we've talked about the interesting milestones coming up for
on-doh equities your layer one anything we miss that that's exciting coming up oh i can guarantee
you both of those things keep us very busy already hundred percent just making sure you didn't miss
anything big we're very very focused on bringing equities on-chain multiple chains i think once
our platform is live as mentioned before we'll start working very actively on making sure these
assets have the right utility on-chain so that essentially ultimately what you are going to be
able to do is do prime brokerage on-chain across the wide variety of asset classes the other thing
i think is going to be very interesting to see i mean we've talked a lot about on those role in
this ecosystem as the issuer but once you have these tokenized stocks on-chain i'm very curious
to see the level of innovation that's going to happen on-chain with these individual tokenized
stocks because that hasn't really ever been the case before where you had a tech stack that allowed
for permissionless innovation and people to build DeFi protocols and systems where the underlying
stocks can move 24/7 globally right so how do you think about even creating a concept similar to
an ETF that all of a sudden becomes trivially easy to do for anyone on-chain how do you think
about creating a robo-advisor or these custom strategies that people would want to build that
becomes pretty trivially easy to do even like um you know recently i personally wanted to buy a
defense ETF or defense stocks we're going to go up but i looked at the defense ETFs out there and
none of them actually had a palantir in any meaningful shape so once these stocks live on-chain it's
going to be pretty trivially easy for me to actually request some things someone a smart contract
robo-advisor whatever it is to say hey i'd like this type of exposure but please add in 20%
pound tier and then you know rebalance quarterly so that level of innovation and what people really
are going to build on these individual tokenized stocks i think is going to be very interesting
to see yeah that would be really cool okay and then finally just looking at a more long-term
horizon if on to succeed what does that look like yeah i think uh you know success to us we're
very mission driven in the sense that we truly believe that what we are building gives global
access to us capital markets to a you know global audience i think that you know is inspired by what
stablecoins have achieved so far and what they continue to do so i think success for on to ultimately
is really creating that open access ecosystem building out the infrastructure for global finance
to start moving on-chain and to help the trad fight institutions as well as every relevant asset
class to move on chain so that ultimately in you know 10 years when people will say wall street
they don't really mean a place in new york but they mean a set of open global rails that
on to help build a very a very different kind of street more like a chain yeah that's right all
right Ian thank you so much for joining me this has been fascinating yeah i can't wait to see
you what you guys are building with equities your lay one thanks Camilla for having me it's been a pleasure